

Full stack software engineer with more than 11 years of experience building technical solutions, covering all areas of the software development lifecycle. Goal-oriented, creating business value with focus on the big picture, knowing when to take shortcuts, and when to evaluate approaches with a holistic view. Self-taught, and a team player, eager to learn and drive change.

Current Interests: Distributed large-scale architecture, Reactive Systems, Chaos Engineering, Domain Driven Design, Continuous Delivery and Evolutionary Architecture.

Tech Highlights

Languages: Java PHP JavaScript Bash Python 3
Frameworks: Maven Gradle Guice Spring GWT Hibernate Hikari Akka JQuery ReactJS
Automation: Docker Ansible Vagrant Jenkins Octopus Pylnvoke
Data: MySQL MariaDB MS SQL Server ElasticSearch Kibana Cassandra RabbitMQ Memcached
Web: Apache2 Nginx
Server: Ubuntu Debian Glassfish Tomcat Jetty

Work Experience

Persequor

Software Engineer / Solution Architect

Current

Solution Architect

- Lead technical teams throughout the development lifecycle, being involved in solution design, implementation, reviewing and operations.
- In charge of the technical roadmap, bridging the gap between business expectations and the technical solution, staying ahead of the curve.
- Provide a cohesive strategy and decision-making framework for engineering the platform, along with relevant documentation, taking into account practices, architecture, technology and processes.
- Collaborate with stakeholders across the organisation, communicating technical goals, concepts, prioritising and setting expectations.
- Mentor technical teams in engineering practices, technical solutions understanding, and technical vision.
- Strong driver of Agile, Devops culture, DDD, TDD, Chaos Engineering and Reactive Systems.

Key milestones:

- Go live of the Omni-Channel Payment Platform, supporting eCommerce, Mobile and POS, with reconciliation across channels.
- Lead the work in order to increase the throughput of the PSP platform by 900% in 1.5 years.
- Lead the migration of the PSP platform to a new Data Centre, in accordance with SLA.
- Lead the work on building a fully automated deployment pipeline.
- PCI-DSS certification of the OmniChannel Platform, with radical changes in encryption and tokenisation.

- Worked as part of an agile team through all the phases of the software development lifecycle of the payment service provider (PSP) solution.
- Engineered integrations to alternative payment methods, acquirers and third party service providers: Klarna, Swish, Mobile Pay, Apple Pay, Valitor, Credorax, among others.
- Engineered support services for the PSP solution: 3D Secure, Credit Card Encryption, Authentication, Transaction Logging, Invoicing, Fundings, etc.
- Engineered the delivery automation of the services to production along with continuous integration.
- Technical Lead on the design and implementation of the OmniChannel API and Platform.
- Team coordination in order to ensure achieving goals within deadlines and expectations, while applying agile values.
- Level 3 troubleshooting of production issues in close collaboration to Support and System Admins.
- Stakeholder on defining architecture and strategies to enhance the platform, including collaboration with other departments and third parties.
- Practices: SCRUM, TDD, Pair Programming, Code Review, CI, CD.

Kiehn Systemer

 Apr 2015 - Oct 2018 7 m



Software Developer / Freelance

- Analyse requirements, design and develop solutions for a Booking system based on GWT.
- Lead development work with colleagues to ensure goal achievement.
- · Refactor of existing modules

PRISMA S.A. (Visa Argentina)

m Mar 2014 - Mar 2015 1 yr 1 m



Java Analyst Programmer

- · Full-stack software development of VisaHome, a credit card management system for consumers
- Queries, Stored Procedures and Functions Development in MS SQL Server.
- · Performed Level 3 troubleshooting of applications issues, in close collaboration with operations.
- Define Architecture and Strategies to enhance the Core Plataform with the Architecture Team
- Lead and Manage outsourced development.
- Define and setup infrastructure for Boton de Pago (Payment Wallet Solution).

IT Resources S.A.

SSR Java Software Developer



• Full-stack software development of an important clinical system from Swiss medical group, through all phases of the software development process.

- Coworkers Assistance Provider in order to ensure growth and professional success.
- Design and Development of CMS Application, and WebServices Application.
- Performed Level 3 troubleshooting of applications issues, in close collaboration with operations.

TALPSA S.A.

Java Developer - R+D

My main responsibility was to lead the mind-set transformation and pave the way in the IT department in order to migrate systems from VB6 to Java.

- Research and Define Development Methods, Design Patters, Frameworks, and Java based Apps Servers to be used.
- Formal Training Organiser on: Maven, Spring, Hibernate, Sonatype Nexus Management (for Maven), CVS
- Architecture Design, Setup, and Maintenance of Development and Production Servers.
- Built GUI Framework for Java based on Swing (Swing, Thread).
- Built Main Company application oriented on Plugins (Swing, RMI, Thread).
- Built SUBE to Accounting system Interface (Socket, Apache commons).

TALPSA S.A.

IT Infrastructure - VB6 Developer

- · Network and Equipment Set Up, Management and Maintenance.
- MS Server 2003, AS400 Management and Maintenance.

2/3 https://cv.estebanm.com/

- Interpretation and Analysis of different department requirements (Mechanics, Human Resources, Accounting) in order to develop these functions into the VB6 based system.
- Migration of AS400 based management software to Visual Basic 6.0.
- Evolutive Development on Existing VB6 based Systems.

Education

Universidad Tecnologica Nacional

= 2008 - 2014 (Not finished)

University Degree: Systems Engineer

Instituto Tecnologico San Bonifacio

= 2005 - 2007

Technical Secondary Education: Technical Engineer in Electronics



English

Professional Proficiency

Spanish

Mother Tongue

https://cv.estebanm.com/